<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nixos on dymc.win</title>
    <link>https://dymc.win/tags/nixos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nixos on dymc.win</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dymc.win/tags/nixos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>making nix-colors talk to neovim</title>
      <link>https://dymc.win/posts/making-nix-colors-talk-to-neovim/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dymc.win/posts/making-nix-colors-talk-to-neovim/</guid>
      <description>I recently started fiddling around with home-managerifying my neovim config. After moving across most of my stuff I came across the problem of how to hook things up with with nix-colors so that my neovim theme would follow color changes in home-manager.
Luckily, I came across this handy little plugin from the lovely mini.nvim suite of plugins which lets you create your own theme with your custom colors.
Beneath is a little snippet of how you could make it all happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tailscale, caddy, and nixos containers - a match made in heaven</title>
      <link>https://dymc.win/posts/tailscale-caddy-nixos-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dymc.win/posts/tailscale-caddy-nixos-containers/</guid>
      <description>For a little while now I&amp;rsquo;ve been running some services (jellyfin etc.) on an old laptop in my house. I&amp;rsquo;m not trying to sound like a podcast ad but as a networking novice, the simplicity tailscale brings to accessing these services remotely is very nice. Until recently though, I had been accessing my services like a heathen with http and port numbers (eg http://tailscale-ip:service-port). This works and is perfectly secure thanks to tailscale though it lacks a certain finesse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>theming nirvana</title>
      <link>https://dymc.win/posts/nix-colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dymc.win/posts/nix-colors/</guid>
      <description>As I fall deeper and deeper down the nixos rabbit hole, I find myself becoming more and more obsessed with controlling every little thing on my computers declaratively. It starts with: &amp;lsquo;oh this is cool I can specify which desktop environment to use in my configuration.nix&amp;rsquo;. Next thing you know you&amp;rsquo;ve discovered home-manager and every program on every linux system you use needs to be controlled in your nix-config. Of course this slightly insane approach has its downsides; it also opens some doors though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>translating docker to nix?!</title>
      <link>https://dymc.win/posts/docker-on-nixos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dymc.win/posts/docker-on-nixos/</guid>
      <description>In my opinion, there are moments when the convenience of docker and its surrounding ecosystem can&amp;rsquo;t be beat. I&amp;rsquo;ve been dabbling in the self hosting world and oftentimes the best maintained packaging option is a docker image. As a result of this I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with the nixos approach to managing docker containers.
nix -&amp;gt; docker compose -&amp;gt; docker run To illustrate how to translate a simple example from the world of docker to nix let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at the config for my searxng instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>simple nixos config for vps static site</title>
      <link>https://dymc.win/posts/simple-nixos-config-for-static-site-on-vps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dymc.win/posts/simple-nixos-config-for-static-site-on-vps/</guid>
      <description>Setting up a little static site is something I&amp;rsquo;ve done a few different times on a few different operating systems. It&amp;rsquo;s a slightly fiddly task with a few disparate jobs that all need looking after: ssh, let&amp;rsquo;s encrypt, nginx. In my opinion, it is one of the moments where consolidating all the little bits and bobs you need to setup into one common configuration is very useful.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through a bit of the nixos config I&amp;rsquo;ve got for my vps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>multi user qtile fiddling</title>
      <link>https://dymc.win/posts/multi-user-qtile-fiddling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dymc.win/posts/multi-user-qtile-fiddling/</guid>
      <description>This post is going to detail how I solved a very particular problem I had created for myself. First, a quick description of the problem. I use home-manager on nixos to declaratively configure what happens on my computer. In the cases where home-manager does not expose sufficient configuration options for my liking (qtile for example), I instead link a configuration file from my nixos config to where it belongs in my home using xdg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>declarative firefox config with home-manager on nixos</title>
      <link>https://dymc.win/posts/declarative-firefox-config-with-home-manager-on-nixos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dymc.win/posts/declarative-firefox-config-with-home-manager-on-nixos/</guid>
      <description>As a man who finds himself reinstalling his OS more than is probably sensible, any opportunity to minimise the post install admin of sorting out all your settings is an attractive one. With that in mind lets take a look at some of the firefox (my current browser of choice) configuration options avilable to you through home-manager. This assumes you have some sort of home-manager setup working. If you do not I found this friendly githubber&amp;rsquo;s templates to be very helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
